The Imagawa army's vanguard,
lead by Matsudaira Motoyasu, has surrounded Marune Fortress with a force of 3,000 men.
The other fortresses are
under attack as well,
and the total enemy force is
believed to exceed 25,000 men.
So, they did come while we were gone.
It's finally started.
The biggest event of Lord
Nobunaga's Ambition...
Oda's finished.
"Owari" means "finished" in Japanese anyway.
That joke only gets five points, Princess.
We need to counterattack.
It's impossible.
Our force only numbers 3,000—
Give up and it's game over.
Nobuna, you can win.
No. Against Imagawa Yoshimoto,
only you could.
Are you sure?
Is the Oda clan going to survive?
Yeah.
The plan is...
No need to say it.
Monkey.
You're fired.
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Why?
Because you acted without my permission.
You ignored my orders and
went ahead on your own.
Of course you're fired.
But I...
You left without a word to me.
That's too selfish.
I don't want to hear
another word from you.
Nobuna...
Don't do any other unnecessary things.
Yoshiharu was
concerned about you.
And he didn't need to be!
But Monkey has the
power to see the future!
He may know how to win...
If we hadn't rushed here,
everyone would've died.
Or did you go with full knowledge that you would die?
Wait a second!
Sure, this wasn't in the game,
so I was in trouble, but...
You said that you'd make
my dream come true,
but those were just words!
I hate liars like you!
Marune and Washidzu are under
attack by Matsudaira Motoyasu,
Asahina Yasutomo, and their 3,000.
Oodaka Castle is under
attack by Udono Nagateru.
Narumi Castle by Okabe Motonobu.
They're attacking on all fronts.
It won't be long before they attack Kiyosu.
Where's Lord Nobuna?
After returning from Nagara River,
she went into her room and won't come out.
While Owari's in grave danger!
If only Lord Nobuhide were still alive...
It's just like Nobuna said.
I'm all talk.
I can't do anything by myself.
And because of that, I got
the Kawanamishuu killed.
I'm scum.
But...
you also saved others.
Old man...
A splendid city.
Only Oda Nobuna could create
and defend such a place.
Can we really defeat the Imagawa?
It's a super famous event in history.
It's only after winning this battle
that Oda truly becomes a conquerer.
Is that the future you know?
Yes.
But in that future,
I'm dead, am I not?
Well...
You changed the future to
save Nobuna from suffering.
How can you be certain that the future
where she wins is still possible?
Nobuna is a genius.
She's likely realized this
and decided not to take you to a
battle she has no hope of winning.
Wh-Why?
You said it yourself:
the people whom she loves die.
You know what she's like.
The only way she could show
how she felt was by firing you.
Forgive her.
That fool...
I loved historical simulation games of this period.
I've always loved this era.
I was so happy that the history I learned
in the games could help everyone.
And maybe that made
me change the future.
But still...
because I knew that history,
I was able to save you, Saitou Dousan.
I can save Nobuna, too.
Child, go do the job that only you can do.
History is on my side.
I will go as well.
We stand with Sagara.
We will follow you into hell itself.
Thanks, everyone.
We've got another tough mission.
So, where do we go?
Okehazama.
According to what I learned from my game,
Imagawa Yoshimoto should be resting there.
We can't launch an attack on our own.
Just locating her camp will be enough.
Nobuna will do the rest.
What if she doesn't believe your report?
She'll believe it.
You'll owe the boss big if we win.
Yeah.
But kid, if you touch our eternal idol, Boss Goemon... we'll kill you.
The boss will never...
be tainted!
Guys...
I've burned all their
provisions and gunpowder.
Okay!
Let's all go kick 'em around, then!
That is Okehazama Mountain!
Mountain?!
Okehazama is a mountain.
So, the game and reality are different?
Oda never attacked a mountain
in the TV shows, either!
Did changing the future turn
Okehazama into a mountain?
Did I take the wrong
choice at the route split,
and now I'm heading for a bad end?!
Save me, Goemon!
S-Stay calm!
Get off me!
Kill!
There's never a dull
moment with you, Monkey.
Nobukatsu.
No... Nobusumi?
I lose.
I have completely lost this one.
What's got you down?
Shut up.
And what are you doing here, anyway?
Let me help, too.
I want to help my sister.
Too bad.
My plan's through.
If Okehazama's a mountain,
we can't launch a sneak attack on it.
Um, there's a flat part of
Okehazama, not just the mountain.
Once Matsudaira's taken Marune,
they can take the lead to Kiyosu.
But our force has suffered
heavy casualties.
Liar.
Motoyasu's a crafty one.
She'd never fight like that.
Matsudaira's force is
to proceed onwards.
Understood?
Indeed.
The Mikawa country samurai can be
the ones to take all the damage.
We will enter the capital
elegantly and unscathed.
That is how a noble fights.
That's definitely it. It's Yoshimoto's camp.
This place doesn't have a name,
but we locals call it Okehazama.
Then it's decided.
A sneak attack here and,
just like the game, Oda wins.
Nobusumi, you stall them.
Stall them?
This is the only place a
sneak attack will work.
Use the girls to serve sake
to their army and buy time.
Leave that to me.
I'll seduce Yoshimoto.
Master Nobusumi, you cheater!
Take care of us after the
job's done, too. Okay?
Of course I will!
As much as it pisses me off,
I'm counting on you.
We can't stay holed up in our castle!
Yoshimoto's first priority
is to make it to Kyoto.
If we don't attack her, she
may very well ignore Kiyosu.
If we don't fight, we'll be destroyed.
Two points.
Your retainers are divided
in their opinions.
Without you, no decision will be reached.
Please...
Where's Monkey?
Nowhere to be found in the castle.
I see.
Even a dog doesn't forget
a favor it's received,
but I guess a monkey does.
This is for the best.
Hurry!
We need to hurry and tell Nobuna!
Imagawa ninjas?
So, you found Yoshimoto's camp.
Impressive.
A ninja! A real ninja!
Hey! I'm a real ninja, too!
Sagara, I'll hold them off.
Hurry and get to the princess!
You dummy!
I can't leave you here and run!
You're the dummy.
Somebody must tell Nobuna
the location of their camp.
B-But...
Go do the job that only you can do.
Don't worry, kid.
Leave those two to us.
Guys...
Stay alive!
Damn it!
Excellent dodge.
I, Hattori Hanzou,
never let my prey escape.
Hattori Hanzou... Motoyasu's ninja?
Nobody has ever seen me and lived.
Then I'll pretend I didn't see you.
Is this it?
I'm sorry, Nobuna.
You really are nothing but talk.
Did you forget your promise with me?
I can't make everyone else fight
and then give up myself!
I commend your fighting spirit.
But it's useless.
Give it up.
I can't beat him in a straight fight.
But I can...
Imagawa Yoshimoto is never going
to let Motoyasu have Mikawa.
One of these days, she'll sacrifice
Motoyasu for her own ambitions.
If Motoyasu wants independence, now's the time!
So, you would have my lord rebel?
She doesn't need to.
Nobuna will defeat Imagawa.
That fool Oda could
never defeat Imagawa.
She can!
The battle of Okehazama will
end with Oda's victory.
So you're Monkey?
You know m—
If Oda attacks Mikawa after her
victory, then we gain nothing.
Nobuna will form an
alliance with Motoyasu.
I'll make her.
Then you're free to try.
But if you don't keep your promise,
someday I will come to kill you.
I'll make it back to Nobuna.
That is...
my Okehazama.
Washidzu and Marune have both fallen.
Our forces have been wiped out.
Both have fallen?
Surrender!
We must surrender!
And hand the princess over to the enemy?
No retainer should ever speak those words.
Zero points.
Stupid girl.
And you're a man who's whining like a girl!
Monkey!
Why are you...?
Blood?
How did you get that wound?
Forget that.
I've found Imagawa Yoshimoto's camp.
At the base of Okehazama Mountain on the east side.
There's a force of approximately 5,000.
They're resting and completely cut
off from the rest of their forces.
Nobusumi's group is stalling them.
This is all I can do.
What kind of future do you see?
It's your path to follow, Nobuna.
You choose what to do.
I'll shut up and follow you.
I see.
Twenty years to a man...
are but a single day
as seen from heaven.
Is there anyone born who
does not someday die?
The Atsumori dance.
You're ready, Nobuna.
We will attack the Imagawa
camp with all our forces!
Since we're here at Atsuta Shrine,
why not offer a prayer
to the gods for victory?
Good idea.
How long are you gonna
leave this country a mess?
From now on, I'll take over for
you and protect the people.
Got it?
If you've got that, then make sure I win.
We clear?
The god sitting in the back of the shrine tells me we're gonna win for sure.
Looks like the gods are pissed.
This is divine providence.
The rain will provide cover as we attack!
The enemy's at Okehazama!
Look at this rain.
I can't even play with my ball.
Huh? Where did young
Nobusumi and his friends go?
We haven't seen them for a while.
Our target is Imagawa Yoshimoto, and her alone!
All forces, advance!
Wh-What's going on?!
An enemy attack!
All forces intercept!
It's no good!
They're all drunk, and we
can't fight in this rain!
Out of the way!
What about their camp?
General Katsuie is on her way.
Someone, protect me!
E-Everyone?
Where have you gone to?
Imagawa Yoshimoto, prepare to die!
H-How dare you?!
This is the way of the world.
Your life is mine!
I don't want to die!
I don't want to be killed here!
Wait, Katsuie!
Don't kill her!
It's a waste!
If we kill a hot girl like that,
Stop... Stop...
I'll regret it the rest of my life.
Don't kill her.
Please!
I won't kill her...
I won't kill her, so stop fondling my breasts!
Glad you understand.
I've been tainted.
Wh-Who are you?
Nobuna's retainer. Sagara Yoshiharu.
Imagawa Yoshimoto,
the war is over.
Surrender.
I-I can't...
It's a total waste for a cute
girl like you to die here.
I-I suppose there's no alternative.
I'll let you off easy, just this
time, so you don't look bad.
Thanks. I mean it.
With Yoshimoto's surrender,
her forces scattered,
and the Imagawa clan, known as the
strongest in the east, fell from power.
It's thanks to you.
Yeah?
Then I need to receive a reward.
Okay, then.
I heard from Katsuie.
You tainted her by
grabbing her breasts!
No, that's a misunderstanding.
And you let Yoshimoto off
because she was cute!
That's also a misunderstanding.
Now, Princess, a victory cheer.
I know already.
Let's go!
Hip-hip-hooray!
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician
Episode Five
Strategy of
the Genius Tactician